Gloria Ho

Web Developer

Forest Hills, NY (646) 535 - 3215 gloria@gloria-ho.com linkedin.com/in/gloria-ho github.com/gloria-ho gloria-ho.com

Hard working web developer with a strong background in management, a newfound passion for programming. Able to build a web presence from concept and design to writing code. Since 2016, a self-directed learner, regular attendee of tech meetups and hackathons, and an open-source project contributor. Free time is spent self teaching French, travelling, tinkering with fountain pens, knitting, and volunteering.

Technical Skills

Ruby / Ruby on Rails JavaScript / ES6 / jQuery Python HTML / Sass / CSS Git
Bootstrap Bash

PostgreSQL / MySQL RESTful APIs / AJAX

Technical Projects

Travel Tracker Web App

Rails, PostgreSQL, User Authentication, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX

- User can create and manage trip itineraries and funds.
- User can create and manage group members to attach to trips.

Book Search Web App (contributor) Rails, PostgreSQL, User Authentication, JavaScript, API, AJAX

- User can search for and read previews for books, as well as read and write reviews.
- User can add, edit, and delete book progress to profile.

Admin Panel Web App

Rails, PostgreSQL, User Authentication, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX

- Administrator can create, view, edit, and delete data.
- Groups of cohorts are created by joining data from the class, teacher, and student tables.

R-umblr Blog Website

Sinatra, PostgreSQL, User Authentication, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX

- User management and restricted access via user authentication.
- User can read, write, edit, and delete blog entries.

Pokedex Website

JavaScript, API, ¡Query, AJAX, Bootstrap, Sass

• Responsive design with animations, pulls and displays data from an external API.

Movie Info Website

Python, HTML5, CSS

• Responsive website that displays movie information and trailers from an external source.

Education

New York Code + Design Academy, New York, NY Udacity, Udacity.com

Software Engineering Intensive
Intro Into Programming Nanodegree
30 Credits / Commercial Photography

2017 2005 - 2006

2018

LaGuardia Community College, LIC, NY

30 Credits / Commercial Photography

2003 - 200

Experience

Assistant Manager

Binex Line Corp., Fort Lee, NJ

01/2010 - 08/2016

- Significantly increased productivity and efficiency by developing new training procedures
- Led an import/sales team of 5 employee
- Managed accounting as well as high profile clients

Assistant Manager

Worldwide Axcess, New York, NY

09/2008 - 12/2009

 Coordinated projects from conception/design to proofing/manufacturing and import/distribution for high profile accounts including Coty, Estee Lauder, Bacardi, and Warner

Assistant Manager

Momofuku Restaurant, New York, NY

07/2006 - 08/2008

Oversaw schedules, payroll, accounting, and HR and organized the opening of new branches